<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nuno Nebeker</title><link>https://blog.nebeker.tech/posts/</link><description>Nuno Nebeker's personal website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2021, Nuno Nebeker; All rights reserved. Using Hugo and Color Your World.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 20:00:24 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.nebeker.tech/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Every Project Needs Accessibility</title><link>https://blog.nebeker.tech/posts/every-project-needs-accessibility/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 20:00:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebeker.tech/posts/every-project-needs-accessibility/</guid><description>Today is Global Accessibility Awareness Day. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have the time or inclination to read my post, read this instead: W3C-WAI - Easy Checks – A First Review of Web Accessibility. If you can, read both!
When you build your shiny new website or web app remember:
If somebody with a motor disability can tab through it, so can you when your hands are busy. If somebody with a visual impairment can use your website with a screen reader, it&amp;rsquo;ll be easy for you to use it with your voice assistant.</description></item><item><title>How I Use Github as a CMS</title><link>https://blog.nebeker.tech/posts/how-i-use-github-as-a-cms/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 20:02:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebeker.tech/posts/how-i-use-github-as-a-cms/</guid><description>There are many blogging and wiki options out there, and there are many factors that go into the decision to use one over another. I’ve used WordPress, in both its open source and hosted versions, and I’ve hand-crafted HTML and CSS when that’s what the project called for. I make no claims to know what the one-and-only blogging solution is, because I don’t think that exists.
My Stack What I’m looking for is:</description></item><item><title>Alice & Bob Communicating as Humans</title><link>https://blog.nebeker.tech/posts/alice-and-bob-communicating-as-humans/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 16:04:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebeker.tech/posts/alice-and-bob-communicating-as-humans/</guid><description>This post was originally published on LinkedIn. I&amp;rsquo;m making it available here in a bilingual format, with no tracking or metrics. If you like it, there&amp;rsquo;s nowhere to click, but do reach out and let me know.
Let&amp;rsquo;s Talk Communication! Our good friends Alice and Bob need to communicate about something, so they use the coolest protocol out there, except they&amp;rsquo;re humans and they&amp;rsquo;re very different people.
Regardless of whether they&amp;rsquo;re using RFC 1149 IP over Avian Carriers or the Signal Protocol, their biggest challenge is taking information from one&amp;rsquo;s model of the world all the way into the other&amp;rsquo;s.</description></item><item><title>The Thingy Didn't Do the Thing!</title><link>https://blog.nebeker.tech/posts/the-thingy-didnt-do-the-thing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 19:04:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebeker.tech/posts/the-thingy-didnt-do-the-thing/</guid><description>I have some thoughts to share on user interface design. This is from the perspective of somebody who is involved in interface design, as a full-stack developer. The reader may not consider themselves to be involved in interface design, but if their work does things that interact with humans - that &amp;ldquo;interface,&amp;rdquo; if you will - they probably are. These thoughts have to do with taking responsibility for our designs, and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to make the reader uncomfortable with their own work or bring mine into play, so let&amp;rsquo;s consider a fictionalized scenario.</description></item><item><title>Owning My Words</title><link>https://blog.nebeker.tech/posts/owning-my-words/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 17:41:05 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebeker.tech/posts/owning-my-words/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had this little website for almost three years and only made a handful of posts. There are other platforms with websites and apps that don&amp;rsquo;t require me to create new Markdown files via CLI and rebuild and push a website. They also have much wider reach - immeasurably so.
As the sands of the internet continue to shift, one may want to ask the questions &amp;ldquo;are those advantages?&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;are they enough?</description></item><item><title>AccessibleDocTool - creating accessible documents</title><link>https://blog.nebeker.tech/posts/accessibledoctool/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 21:48:41 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebeker.tech/posts/accessibledoctool/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten involved in a few different activities that warrant the creation of documents that are accessible to blind and visually impaired people. In general, that means careful font and visual style selection, for better visual readability, and proper use of semantics and structure, for screen reader use. It&amp;rsquo;s also a good idea to provide different file formats - different strokes for different folks, right?
That either sounds like a lot of work, or like a task that&amp;rsquo;s a perfect candidate for templates and automation.</description></item><item><title>eul</title><link>https://blog.nebeker.tech/posts/eul/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 22:34:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebeker.tech/posts/eul/</guid><description>This week, I localized eul into Portuguese. It&amp;rsquo;s a system monitor for macOS that supports Big Sur, including some nice widgets.</description></item><item><title>Rectangle</title><link>https://blog.nebeker.tech/posts/rectangle/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 19:05:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebeker.tech/posts/rectangle/</guid><description>Last week, I contributed a Portuguese (Portugal) localization to the Rectangle app.
It&amp;rsquo;s a window manager for macOS and I highly recommend it!</description></item><item><title>My First Post</title><link>https://blog.nebeker.tech/posts/my-first-post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 15:13:31 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebeker.tech/posts/my-first-post/</guid><description>Website created.</description></item></channel></rss>